### PIA MARIA MALIK

#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

+91 9999947931

p91malik@gmail.com

# **Personal Profile**

Age: 28

Languages: English, Hindi, Persian, Urdu

Current Employment:

PhD Scholar, Department of History, Faculty of Social Sciences, University of Delhi (Enrolled October 2017)

Editorial Assistant for The Indian Economic and Social History Review. (Since July 2017)

My doctoral research falls under the rubric of a feminist social and intellectual history, in which I am studying the dynamics of the construction and delineation of power of a group of Sufi masters, studied through their discursive statements as wielders of spiritual (and therefore social) authority within a 'Chishti' fraternity, concentrating on their maneuvers in the Deccan over the period of the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries. Out of a body of *khalīfūs* (disciples), one (and occasionally more, but rarely in the same geographical area) would claim supremacy over the others and become *pīr* (master) in his own right. Focusing on four saints, my study unpacks the social, cultural, and intellectual contexts in which they each chose to claim a place of authority, as well as the particular textual resources and techniques that each had to deploy in order to become a *pīr*, in which they accessed pan-Islamicate networks of Chishti Sufism, Islamic identities, and elite discourses as explicated through a specific Persianate literary culture. The project aims at foregrounding the conceptual, material, and imaginal dimensions of charisma in a chosen locality (the Deccan), which was nevertheless connected to the rest of the Islamic world through networks, particularly those centred on pilgrimage and the accumulation and extension of bodies of knowledge.

### **Educational Qualifications**

- Currently enrolled as PhD scholar at the Department of History, Faculty of Social Sciences, Delhi University.
  - Thesis titled "Becoming Pir: A Social History of Power among the early Deccani Shaykhs".
- I Division, M.Phil History, Department of History, Faculty of Social Sciences, Delhi University. (2014-2016)
  - Thesis titled "Disentangling the Chishti silsila: The Husaini tarīqa and the Jawāmi' al-Kalim" Awarded Distinction.
- 3. I Division, M.A. in Medieval Indian History from Faculty of Social Sciences, University of Delhi affiliated to Lady Shri Ram College (2012-2014).
- 4. II Division, B.A. (Hons.) History from St. Stephens College, University of Delhi (2009-2012).

# **Additional Qualifications**

- Completed Certificate course in Persian from Iran Culture House, Delhi, Level One (91%) and Level Two (86%).
- Grade 8 concert pianist certified by Trinity College, London.
- Cleared SAT with a score of 2250 (99.7th percentile) (2008).

# Work Experience

- Taught SAT Classes for TestRocker in 2013-14 Focus on Reading and Writing.
- Students' Organising Committee for Conference on "Crossing Boundaries" held in Delhi University, Department of History, on 27th-28th February, 2017.
- Member of Seminar Committee, Department of History, Delhi University, from 2015-present.
- Presented Paper titled, "The Noble Sayyid with Tangled Locks: The Husaini tariqa and the Jawami" al-Kalim" at Research Scholars' Conference, Delhi University, held on 6th-8th March, 2017.
- Student Organising Committee for Global History Conference organised by the Weatherhead Initiative at Delhi University. 3<sup>rd</sup>-5<sup>th</sup> December 2017. On Empires in Global History.
- Completed workshop on Critical Philosophy of Race with Divya Dwivedi and Roberto Bernasconi at IIT Delhi, 13-17 November, 2017.
- Presented Paper titled, "The Jawāmi" al-Kalim and the weaving of a Sufi tarīqa" at UGC-SAP sponsored Centre for English Studies, Jawaharlal Nehru University National Young Researchers' Conference on "Literature and the Mystical Foundations of Authority" 22-23 February 2018.

- Presented paper 'The 'ilm of the Sufi in a fifteenth century text: Modes of Reading the pīr in the Javāmi' al-Kalim' Research Scholars' Conference 2018, University of Delhi, Department of History, 13-15 March, 2018.
- Organising Committee for Conference on 'Chronologies and Connections, and the Historiographies that sustain them' at Delhi University, Department of History, on 2<sup>nd</sup>-3<sup>rd</sup> March, 2019.
- Organising Committee for Research Scholars' Conference on 'Source and Sensibility' at Delhi University, Department of History, on 11th-13th March, 2019.

# **Publications**

- Book review of Mohammed Suleman Siddiqi, The Junaydi Sufis of the Deccan: Discovery of a
  Seventeenth Century Scroll. New Delhi: Primus, 2014. In The Indian Economic and Social History
  Review, Vol. 54, No. 2 (March 2017), pp. 284-286.
- Book review of Suleiman Mourad, The Mosaic of Islam: A Conversation with Perry Anderson. New Delhi: Three Essays Collective, 2017. In The Book Review India, Vol 42, No. 1 (2018), p. 46.
- Book Review of Carl W. Ernst, It's not Just Academic!: Essays in Sufism and Islamic Studies. New Delhi: Yoda Press, 2018. In The Book Review India, Vol. 42, No. 9 (2018), p. 33.